Ken Ren

North York, ON M2M 4H9 ken.ren98@gmail.com

647 355 0239

Portfolio: https://kenren.top/

Computer Science bachelor from York University, having solid foundation on Java, JavaScript, and Python coding, also familiar with C / C++. Worked with Spring Framework and MERN stack on multiple projects. Positive and communicative participant during teamwork. Very familiar with software deployment, operation, and networking. Very familiar with virtual environment, cloud environment and all three major types of OS and related automation tools - FreeBSD, Linux (Both Fedora and Debian Based branches) and Windows family. Also, Having handful experience with Docker and LXC / LXD. And extra experiences with Computer Vision / Machine Learning / Computer Graphics and Computer Security including topics like Neural Networks, Image Processing, Programmable Shaders, Code analysis and Penetration testing, etc.

Highly skilled technician offering 5+ years' experience of part-time Computer building and repairing, capable of repairing Laptop / PC / MacBook / Cellphone / iPhone up to component level. Also, familiar with all kinds of hardware / consumer electronic, their advantages, and disadvantages, keep updated all the time. Versatile media professional, hosting multiple hardware review / product demonstration channels with over 20,000 subscribers in total. Equipped with knowledge of different workflows of vary industries and consumers. Having a strong communication skill, assisting customers with their technical issues, and helping them find the right product effectively, sold more than 2000 computers over last 3 years. Having a handful firsthand experience with BIOS / UEFI and Driver issues, familiar with all kinds of protocols and form factors. Also being able to explain the fundamental organization of computer system to a certain degree.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere.

Education

Highest Level of Education: Bachelor's Degree

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science York University - Toronto, ON January 2019 to May 2023

Work Experience

Full-time Technician

Canada Computers and Electronics

Sept 2023 to Present

- PC design / build / repair, PC component repair.
- Laptop Repair up to component level
- Software issue resolving, Windows / MacOS

Part-time Technician and Hardware Reviewer

Mr.Leaves Electronics and Net Woking Inc.

October 2018 to Present

- Server Sale, Rental and Maintenance / Game Server Rental (https://panel.mr-leaves.com/)
- Cloud Service development, deployment, and Maintenance
- (Alibaba, Tencent, AWS, Azure)
- Special System Building for Mining and Machine Learning purpose (Linux/BSD Based)
- Automation Development and Deployment for small to medium sized business
- Home/Business networking design and deployment

- PC design / build / repair / resell, PC component resell and repair.
- Developed and conducted video channels with over 20,000 subscribers, received sponsorship and review from companies.
- Focused on technology tutorial and hardware reviews. Running several channels in different platform with positive feedback.

Part-time Computer Technician

Self Employment - Toronto, ON September 2015 to September 2018

- PC and Laptop build / refurbish / repair / resell
- Apple product repair/ upgrade, Clover/OpenCore EFI configuring.
- Software problems resolve
- Network structure design
- Multi-purpose server design and deploy.
- TrueNAS / Unraid ZFS deployment experiences

Projects and Skills

Event Posting and Event Planning Platform

Utilize Cognito as User store to improve scalability (Region based App using same user store) and SNS for password-less login experience. EC2 for hosting and S3 as affordable alternative to CDNs. VUE frontend plus ExpressJS backend and MongoDB datastore with Redis Cache. Micro Services design combined with Docker compose and container image as deliverable for potential CI/CD needs using GitHub Action or Jenkins.

Role: Majority of App Design and Prototyping (Product Manager), draft UI design, Full Stack Coding and AWS Cloud Development.

HelpDesk WebApp using WebSocket.

Using WebSocket as custom API for Live communication between clients, allow anonymous user to be served by different agents, offer management, file/image attachments and chatting session transfer functions. React frontend plus ExpressJS backend.

Role: Engaged in Software Design and was the primary Author of the SRS. Took the lead in implementing WebSocket-related functions, ensuring real-time communication capabilities. Actively participated in Pan Testing, focusing on static code analysis to enhance code quality. Further Bug fixing and going through a security checklist. Demo deployment and further Pan test with NGFW deployed.

· Indoor Golf Automation

Implemented on-site automation for two stores, streamlining management and operations with enhanced automation capabilities. Utilized REST API and MQTT protocol to synchronize with the cloud, enabling automation and states syncing with cloud for multiple devices including Projectors, PCs, Light switches, motion sensors and security cameras and doors. Allow unmanned stores work swimmingly with customer order online.

Role: Led the team in integrating the automation system, ensuring seamless synchronization with the cloud. Guide the client with device purchasing and store designing. Presented the automation system to stakeholders, gathering feedback for further improvements or addon functions.

• Game Server Hosting, Rental, and Datacenter Maintenance

Integrated the Pterodactyl panel for streamlined management and operations of over 20 server nodes across 3 Datacenters. Utilized Proxmox LXC + Docker for the Wings Backend, with the front end hosted in the main Datacenter. Implemented VLAN for network isolation and properly configured network policies for internal security. Employed pfSense as an IPS, actively preventing potential threats and data leaks. Established a comprehensive backup plan, ensuring data recovery and disaster recovery capabilities and Ceph for HA, ensuring uninterrupted services even during hardware failures.

Role: Played a pivotal role in designing and maintaining the DataCenter infrastructure. Led the team in integrating the Pterodactyl panel and ensuring high availability using Ceph. Network Design and implementation. Oversaw the backup and recovery processes, ensuring data integrity.

See more detail or source code at my Portfolio page: <u>Dexuan Ren (Ken Ren)</u>

Languages

- Chinese Advanced
- English Advanced

Links

Portfolio: Dexuan Ren (Ken Ren)

GitHub: KenRen98 (Dexuan Ren) (github.com)

LinkedIn: Dexuan (Ken) Ren | LinkedIn